unity a cross-platform game engine for building 2d and 3d experiences made
unity 一个用于构建 2d 和 3d 体验的跨平台游戏引擎，以使
famous for democratizing the immense challenge of game development it was
游戏开发的巨大挑战民主化而闻名，它
created in copenhagen denmark and first released in 2005. today it's the magic
在丹麦哥本哈根创建并于 2005 年首次发布。如今，它是
behind many popular games like the 2d among us
许多流行游戏背后的魔力，例如我们当中的 2d 和
the 3d monument valley augmented reality apps like pokemon go first-person
3d 纪念碑谷 增强现实应用程序，例如 pokemon go 第一人称
shooters like escape from tarkov as well as interactive simulations and
射击游戏，例如逃离塔科夫，以及
animations beyond the gaming industry the engine itself is written in c plus
游戏行业之外的交互式模拟和动画引擎本身是用 c plus plus 编写的，
plus but allows developers to write their code in the more approachable c
但允许开发人员用更平易近人的 c 语言编写代码
sharp in addition it provides a powerful graphical editor allowing you to draw
此外，它还提供了一个强大的图形编辑器，允许您
shapes work with cameras and apply materials without having to write a
使用相机绘制形状并应用材料，而无需编写
single line of code every game object can have a variety of components like a
一行代码每个游戏对象都可以有各种组件，如
mesh to define its actual physical shape a mesh renderer to apply materials and
网格来定义其实际物理形状 网格渲染器应用 物体的材质和
lighting to an object and physics components like rigidbody and colliders
光照以及模拟物体的刚体和对撞机等物理组件
that simulate things like gravity and collisions in the real world and finally
就像现实世界中的重力和碰撞一样，最后
you can extend an object with your own c sharp code to make it do something
你可以用你自己的 c 语言代码扩展一个对象，让它做一些
interesting like take hit points when it runs into a bad guy to build your first
有趣的事情，比如当它遇到一个坏人时获得生命值来构建你的第一个
video game right now install unity hub create a new project then open up the
视频游戏现在安装统一集线器创建一个新项目，然后打开
editor you'll be greeted with a 3d scene that contains a light source and a
编辑器，您将看到一个包含光源和
camera a scene is like a game level that you're developing while the camera is
相机的 3d 场景。场景就像您正在开发的游戏关卡，而相机
the point of view of the player to create a game of dodgeball let's add a
是玩家的视角创建一个躲避球游戏让我们添加一个
plane to be the ground a cylinder for the player and a sphere for the ball
平面作为地面玩家的圆柱体和球的球体
select an object then hit y on your keyboard to move rotate and scale it to
选择一个对象然后按键盘上的 y移动旋转并根据
your liking hit the play button and notice how these shapes don't do
自己的喜好缩放它按播放按钮并注意这些 形状没有
anything but if we add a rigid body to the objects all of a sudden they're now
任何作用，但如果我们突然给物体添加一个刚体，它们现在会
impacted by the laws of gravity currently they look pretty boring but we
受到万有引力定律的影响，目前它们看起来很无聊，但我们
can make them look cool by creating a material and then drag it onto the
可以通过创建一个材质然后拖动它来让它们看起来很酷到
shapes and now to make this game playable let's add a script component to
形状上 现在为了让这个游戏可玩，让我们向它添加一个脚本组件
it and then open it in vs code it contains a class with two methods to
，然后在 vs 代码中打开它，它包含一个类，其中包含两个方法来
implement your code start is called once at the very beginning of the game while
实现你的代码 start在游戏开始时调用一次，而
update is called on every frame while the game is being played and there's
update 在每一帧上调用在玩游戏的同时，还有一个
also fixed update that runs at the same frame rate as the physics engine now to
固定更新，它以与物理引擎相同的帧速率运行，
move our player around we can define a public property for the rigid body which
现在我们可以为刚体定义一个公共属性，其中
contains a bunch of different properties and methods to move the object around
包含许多不同的属性和方法来移动
now assign an actual value from the game to that property by dragging the rigid
现在通过
body component to it in the editor in the fixed update method we can first use
在编辑器中将刚体组件拖动到该属性中，在固定更新方法中将游戏中的实际值分配给该属性，我们可以首先使用
input to detect when a user presses the arrow keys and then call the move
输入来检测用户何时按下箭头键，然后调用移动
position method on the rigid body to move it hit the play button and you
位置方法 在刚体上移动它，点击播放按钮，你
should now be able to move your player around from there we can add a script to
现在应该可以从
the ball that will add force to it when the game starts to roll it across the
那里移动你的玩家了 在屏幕上滚动它
screen and we can also run code when the two objects collide by defining the on
，我们还可以在两个对象发生碰撞时运行代码，通过定义 on
collision enter method congratulations you just built a video game this has
collision enter 方法恭喜你刚刚构建了一个视频游戏
been unity in 100 seconds if you want to see more short videos like this hit the
如果你想看到更多这样的短视频，这已经在 100 秒内统一了点击
like button and subscribe and let me know if you want to see a full unity
喜欢按钮并订阅，如果你想在评论中看到完整的统一
tutorial in the comments thanks for watching and i will see you in the next
教程，请告诉我谢谢观看，我会在下
one
一个